# Sreenadh Madappura

## **Java Full Stack Developer**

Evere, Brussels, Belgium • +32-465271150 • sreenadhm01@gmail.com



m sreenadh-m



sreenadh.dev



sr33nadhm

Seasoned fullstack developer with around 4 years of experience implementing both frontend and backend systems. Well versed in Java, JavaScript and Typescript. Led the re-architecture of the critical platforms that cater to large user bases by enhancing their efficiency.

#### **SKILLS & TOOLS**

Programming Languages - Java, JavaScript

User Interface Development - Angular, React.js, MobX, Material UI, HTML, CSS, jQuery Backend Development - Java Spring Boot, Node.js, Express.js, REST API, Hibernate, JPA

Database Management - MySQL, DB2, PostgreSQL, MongoDB

**Test frameworks –** jest, junit

Message Queues - RabbitMQ, Apache Kafka

Amazon Web Services - DynamoDB, S3, EC2, Lambda, API Gateway, CloudFront

**Google Cloud Platform –** Compute Engine, Cloud Storage, BigQuery

**SVN and Project Management –** Github, Bitbucket, JIRA, Confluence

**DevOps** - Docker, Kubernetes, Jenkins

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## **Full Stack Java Engineer**

May 2023 - Present

ASPL BV, Brussels, Belgium

Responsible for handling internal applications, focusing on UI development in Angular and backend development in Java Spring Boot, Hibernate, and MySQL.

#### **Software Developer**

May 2021 - May 2023

IBM, India

Handled the role of full stack developer in IBM internal application project, taking part in UI development in Ext.js, Angular and backend development in Java Spring Boot and DB2, and CI-CD using Jenkins, Docker.

- Led the development team by delegating tasks and conducting code reviews while also actively participating in development tasks.
- Re-architected the application for migration to IBM Cloud, making necessary configuration changes and addressing compatibility issues for successful migration.
- Acted as the primary point of contact for implementing new features, including requirement gathering, feasibility analysis, and completion of Proof-of-Concepts.
- Implemented new features, conducted bug fixing, code refactoring, and resolved technical debt to improve application quality and performance.
- Successfully migrated the application to a new tech stack, replacing the Ext. is based user interface with Angular.
- Developed a middleware service using Node.js, serving as an interpreter for REST API endpoints and handling static web page serving using Express.js. Additionally, implemented JWT-based authentication for backend API requests.

#### Achievements include:

Successfully handled the application requirements needed for organization restructure of the company.

- Led the re-architecture of the application and its migration to IBM Cloud, utilizing Docker, Kubernetes, and Open Liberty, resulting in a 300% increase in deployment rates.
- Modernized the application to IBM Carbon Design System in Angular, eliminated existing CVE exposures in the backend.

#### **Systems Engineer**

August 2019 - May 2021

Infosys, India

Handled the role of full stack developer for 3 client projects and 1 internal project of Infosys which cater to their employees. Responsible for frontend and backend development for multiple applications, programmed scripts in languages like JavaScript and Python. Projects include:

## Online Video platform - Vuclip

- Implemented and streamlined new features for their backend services, which consists of Java Spring Boot, Hibernate and MySQL.
- Migrated monolithic billing platform services to microservice architecture which increased deployment frequency.
- Implemented backend and frontend changes that helped to onboard more than 4 payment gateway services to their new billing platform.

#### Infosys Internal OTT based project - Infosys Ltd

- Responsible for developing and deploying frontend components for their large Single Page Application in Angular.
- Implemented new features for their backend services with Java Spring Boot, Hibernate, JPA and MongoDB.
- Written and maintained automated test cases in jUnit.
- Collaborated with the UI design team and generated UI components in Angular and integrated the user interface with backend services using REST Api.
- Actively participated in code reviews, monitored and ensured coding practices are being followed.

## <u>Internet Measurement Platform – Comcast Corporation</u>

- Built and deployed features for their Node is application for monitoring internet speeds.
- Developed new features for their data pipeline using Kafka which helped in report generation.
- Handled and actively participated in code reviews and resolved tech debt.
- Performed data analytics and report generation using Elasticsearch and Kibana.
- Generated scripts in Python to process real time data feeds from Elasticsearch

## Online video platform migration - Brightcove Inc

Handled the position of Full Stack Developer for designing and developing new features and plugins which helped them migrate their content and user information to the target platform.

- Programmed more than 5 scripts to assist in the migration and data validation of user and metadata records, ensuring accuracy and completeness.
- Implemented UI components using React, which were integrated with the backend through REST APIs, enabling smooth user interaction and data communication.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### Amrita University, India

August 2017 - May 2019

Master of Computer Applications — Computer Science

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

Winter Internship - Infosys Ltd

January 2019 - May 2019

Completed the internship with Infosys in their Global Education Center, Mysore which included training in Java Microservices with Spring Boot and Angular. A Capstone project was implemented and submitted as part of the internship.

## Microservices with Java, Spring, Docker, Kubernetes - Udemy

Completed certification course from Udemy for Spring Boot Microservices and their containerization using Docker and Kubernetes.

URL: https://ude.my/UC-95990a70-6e31-44fb-bf87-2852161f0d8f/